<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vim Text Editor on Marcelo Bezerra Barboza</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/talks/tags/vim-text-editor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vim Text Editor on Marcelo Bezerra Barboza</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/talks/tags/vim-text-editor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Combining Macros With Conditional Statements in Vim</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/talks/posts/combining-macros-with-conditional-statements-in-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/talks/posts/combining-macros-with-conditional-statements-in-vim/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how I use Vim to insert data fields in a json file with data gathered from a csv file.&#xA;Suppose we have a json file with hundreds of entries like this:&#xA;&amp;#34;01234567891&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;fname&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;john smith&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;level&amp;#34;: 2, &amp;#34;email&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;john.smith@server.net&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;award&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;none&amp;#34; } Now, suppose that a third party gives us a csv file with the awards for some of the people in our csv, possibly not all of them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edit Multiple Lines at Once With Vim</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/talks/posts/edit-multiple-lines-at-once-with-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/talks/posts/edit-multiple-lines-at-once-with-vim/</guid>
      <description>In this post I want to explain how to sort the lines of a csv file while keeping related lines close to one another.&#xA;My friends organize and promote a mathematics competition called OMEG. Every year I help them to keep the list of its participants up to date. It&amp;rsquo;s a csv file whose fields have the following meaning: inep code, full name and exam level (it&amp;rsquo;s an ordinal number, either 1, 2, or 3).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edit Multiple Files at Once With Vim</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/talks/posts/edit-multiple-files-at-once-with-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/talks/posts/edit-multiple-files-at-once-with-vim/</guid>
      <description>Just the other day I engaged in an interesting project with my family. We grabbed the data about this TV Show from IMDb in order to create:&#xA;A PostgreSQL database A presentation in LaTeX using the Beamer document class A statically generated web site with Hugo Once the database was ready everything else was relatively easy thanks to Vim. For instance, to create the presentation we dumped a csv file from our database like this:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
